Contact

jamie.mcdonnell@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ jamiemcdonnell (LinkedIn) www.ui-ux-design.com (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Brand development & policing
Creative Strategy
Design management and production

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
Czech

Jamie McDonnell

User Experience Design Evangelist and Developer - freelance District Prague-West, Czech Republic

Summary

I am an experienced visual brand and front end designer and developer.

As an evangelist of modern front end development demands and techniques, I am forever learning the best ways to offer users a smooth and effective experience

I specialise in web start-up planning and visual design, brand building for new web based startups, web application planning, user flows and wireframing, prototype development and aesthetic, on brand creative design.

I have experience working with big brands such as AVG.com, Monster.com and Vodafone, and apply myself on creative projects with a level of flexability that is always appreciated by my clients.

I understand how to portray a message clearly through sharp typography, structured page layout and rich colour combinations, and have a clear understanding of the internet as a medium, and the technologies at my disposal to transfer ideas from paper effectively to the screen.

Specialties: Visual concept design and development, visual brand asset design, wireframing and application design, responsive web design, HTML3, CSS3, jquery application development, Twitter Bootstrap & WordPress.

I have an accute eye for detail and a knack of converting product specifications into visual advertising messages - Search Engine Optimization knowledge while programming the front end, modern web techniques and technologies, and an ability to learn on the job.

Experience

Freelance Designer / Self Employed User experience designer / developer January 2013 - Present

As a full time freelance front end designer and developer I am working on developing branded user experience for cutting edge start ups.

Drawing from my skills in graphic and brand design I help my clients to develop a visual brand for their online businesses, and a user experience that looks and acts in a manor that reflects their brand values.

As well as designing visual brand attributes, ui style, look and feel, my strong background in front end development enables me to develop production ready front end code to prove ui concepts, organize user testing understanding and responding to the points that are brought to light as a result.

If you are looking for top of class support for your front end design and development challenges, do get in touch and if I have time available to support you I can offer consultation, design assistance or full project support depending on the demands of your project.

I look forward to hearing form you!

eFace2Face, Inc.

User Experience Design Evangelist and Developer November 2012 - November 2014 (2 years 1 month)

At eFace2Face I am responsible for the visual brand, and how it is brought to life visually through the website, our products and way our users experience them.

I work closely with the rest of the team to develop work flows, design features and functionality, and implement new features using a variety of front end coding techniques.

As we move forward, we are paying special attention to the mobile user experience, and provide functionality to a wide range of platforms and browsers.

eFace2Face is a dynamic, fast moving, forward thinking company that is driving forward the bleeding edge of web communication technologies.

AVG

Design Manager

June 2009 - November 2012 (3 years 6 months)

Managing the creative look, feel and consistency of AVG Technologies' web assets.

Evolving new concepts for page, campaign, banner and application component design from sketch to final production-ready design.

Communication regarding brand and design concepts and consistency with external agencies.

Self employed

Freelance Graphic & Interaction Designer 2004 - 2011 (8 years)

Rationalizing user experiences in order to create the architectural foundations of a variety of client websites in the form of wireframes.

Creating branded web design solutions that answer to both the usability and brand expectations of the user.

Programming simple front end solutions in HTML, CSS and Javascript, including jQuery, to facilitate user needs in simple and intuitive ways.

Self employed

Freelance 3d graphic artist 2002 - 2011 (10 years)

Produced 3d visual representations of exhibition stands and installations either as a pitch to win the exhibition work or as visualization for a client. I also produced motion graphic and character animation for presentations and interactive applications.

AVG Technologies SRO

Senior Web / Graphic Designer

August 2009 - December 2010 (1 year 5 months)

Design of all web pages and components, banners, graphics and interaction design. Also print design and creative direction. Some front end coding and management of front end code development from a visual stand-point.

360 Cities s.r.o

Designer / web developer

May 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 4 months)

My role with 360Cities is a varied one - I initially came on board as a freelancer to design some brochures for this now popular and thriving startup. From there I redesigned, branded and coded a bunch of sales orientated pages, and a few prototypes using panorama video and google maps.

This let to me getting hired full time to lead a redesign of the front end application and account management pages while the back end had been reworked by a Ruby developer in the US (The Boss's brother).

Now I lead on anything design, UI or brand related, build new features and over-see any ammendements from a graphic and usability point of view.

I spend a lot of time designing concepts and new business websites for 360 Cities, coding full pages and small behaviors / widgets (such as on the map page www.360cities.net/map) using dhtml, javascript (jquery) and css.

This is one project I have really enjoyed developing...

Monster Technologies
Senior Designer / Art Director
December 2007 - May 2008 (6 months)

Designing new pages, work flows and components for new projects and sites that fall under the Monster.com technologies product. Creating art work, logos and page idents for various countries home and landing pages. Localizing design solutions from external agencies. Writing html, CSS and Actionscript for full pages and page elements such as media components. Assisting in defining and improving site architecture, user experience and work flow through different features and processes users will encounter while using Monster.com.

Monster Technologies Prague Front End Designer April 2007 - December 2007 (9 months)

Developing interfaces for inovative new products in the Labs devision of Monster Technologies using (X + D)HTML, CSS, Photoshop, Illustrator, Flash, Javascript, Actionscript, some ASP.Net

Symbius New Media Designer 2005 - 2006 (2 years) I worked with the Symbius Design studio in Maidenhead, England, as senior Graphic and New Media Designer, producing web design solutions, interactive interfaces, 3D modelling and animation, video editing and effects, and HTML based web design projects. As a small team of 4 people we handled creative make-overs for many top-class clients including ARUP, British Airways, BP (British Petrol) and EcoCentroGen. was the main client contact on all new media projects, and helped guide them through their creative and technical challenges.

Dumfries and Galloway Council IT Technician 2003 - 2004 (2 years)

I worked as a poster / visual material designer and Map Technician initially, but got involved in a wildlife film project that consumed half my career for the council filming, editing and producing DVDs of some rare birds that were found on the South Coast of Scotland. I offered technical support for the planning department in the council, fixing computer issues and providing designs and prints for media when they were taking a project or presentation on the road. During the course of this employment I was working freelance as a designer / animator on a variety of video and web projects.

Education

Cumbria Institute of the Arts

Interaction Design and Character Animation, Interaction design (2000 - 2003)

Reading Art College

NVQ 2, Digital Graphic Design · (1998 - 2000)